Leon Nesbitt

Stationary Engineer

Philadelphia, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Leon-Nesbitt/6de60617a7787cf3

Stationary Engineer with over 20 years of comprehensive experience seeks a rewarding and challenging position within an organization that will best utilize my experience and skills for growth within the company.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Stationary Engineer

Albert Einstein Hospital - Philadelphia, PA - November 2011 to November 2012

Stationary Engineer

Wynmoore, PA - July 2007 to May 2010

Stationary Engineer

Saint Joseph's Hospital - Philadelphia, PA - January 2000 to June 2007

Stationary Engineer

Genesis Elder Care - Philadelphia, PA - November 1998 to January 2000

Stationary Engineer

Pennsylvania Hospital - Philadelphia, PA - May 1995 to September 1998

Stationary Engineer

Ammark Curtis Center - Philadelphia, PA - January 1991 to December 1994

Stationary Engineer

Conrail Corporation - Philadelphia, PA - June 1986 to December 1990

EDUCATION

HVAC Mechanic Universal

Orleans Technical School - Philadelphia, PA 1999

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

SKILLS & ABILITIES:

- Operated and maintained stationary engines and mechanical equipment, such as steam engines, air compressors, generators, motors, turbines, and steam boilers.
- Read meters and gauges or automatic recording devices at specified intervals to verify operating conditions.
- Recorded data, such as temperature of equipment, hours of operation, fuel consumed temperature or pressure, water levels, analysis of flue gases, voltage load, and generator balance.
- Adjusted manual controls or override automatic controls to bring equipment into recommended or prescribed operating ranges, switch to backup equipment or systems, or to shut down equipment.
- Visually inspected equipment at periodic intervals to detect malfunctions or need for repair, adjustment, or lubrication.

- Maintained equipment by tightening fittings, repacking bearings, replacing packing glands, gaskets, valves, recorders, and gauges, and cleaning or replacing burners or other components, using hand and power tools, oil and lubricate equipment.
- Performed water titration tests and pours chemical additives, such as water softener, into treatment tank to prevent scale buildup and to clean boiler lines.
- Recorded operation and maintenance actions taken during shift in operators logbook.